Mohini Patil

Pune, Maharashtra, India ☑ p.mohinin@gmail.com 및 8080179934 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohini-p-351231b1

SUMMARY

Persistent professional equipped with 5.8 years of experience in Product based company as a Functional QA Engineer at Securly Software. Optimized structures and processes to accomplish targets and promote company loyalty. Experienced in SaaS based web and mobile application testing. Seeking to leverage problem solving work ethic to contribute to organization's success as a Manual Tester.

EXPERIENCE

Quality Assurance Engineer Securly Software

July 2021 - Present

Quality Analyst Apollo 24|7

December 2020 - July 2021

Software Engineer Cybage Software Pvt Ltd.

July 2018 - December 2020

PROJECTS

Visitor Management System

Securly Software

- Expertise in testing SaaS based B2C web application in EdTech domain.
- $\cdot \ \text{Mainly performed Functional testing, API testing using Postman \ and UI/UX testing for web \ and iPad \ app.}$
- · Worked closely with development teams, business analysts, and other stakeholders to understand project requirements and functionalities so as to ensure quality throughout the software development lifecycle.
- · Used Jenkins for deploying the latest/fixed code on the test environment and experience in writing basic SQL queries for backend data validations.
- · Responsible for leading quality testing activities including estimation, prioritization, planning, and coordination.
- Responsible for conducting security testing and reporting SSRF and IDOR bugs using Burp suite tool to identify vulnerabilities and ensure data protection.
- · Involved in sprint cycle from the Feature Kickoff meetings till retrospective meeting.
- Provided pre-and post production deployment end to end support and tested every release on production environment for both web (Mac/iOS, Windows browsers) and iPad(iOS) app releases.
- Reported bugs & errors by providing detailed information of those defects to the developers using test management software like JIRA. Worked with the development team to get bugs fixed and proactively assisted the developers to debug issues through effective collaboration.
- Ensured successful deployment of applications on Prod. environment followed by production support.
- · Implemented test techniques, methodologies and tools to achieve high-level of test coverage.
- Proficient in Cross-browser testing and Compatibility testing of web-apps.
- · Performed testing on Dymo Badge printer for web and app for physical badge printing feature.
- · Proficient in working on Browsers Developer tools (Network, Console, Elements, Application).
- Identified automation opportunities in different workflow and worked closely with the Automation Engineers to ensure that the test cases are automated as documented.
- · Responsible for running automation suite on Jenkins and give the error reports to resp. automation QA.
- · Responsible for conducting new feature demo and complete application demos to Business Users.
- · Responsible for training & managing a team of 2 QA resources and assigning them tasks.
- Investigated customer complaints ,resolved their queries and mocked into their system whenever required for understanding their configurations and then correcting them if anything was missing on their end.

• Participated in agile ceremonies/frameworks such as sprint planning, daily stand-ups, estimations and sprint reviews to provide testing status updates and identify potential risks.

Apollo 24 7 - Web & Mobile App

Apollo 24 7

- Reviewed and analyzed system requirements, specifications and technical design documents to provide timely and meaningful feedback.
- · Involved in conducting formal technical reviews, inspection and walkthrough of documents like BRD and SRS.
- Expertise in creating comprehensive test plans and test cases based on functional and technical specifications for e-commerce website.
- Performed thorough regression testing to ensure existing functionality remained intact after new changes or updates were implemented.
- Conducted Integration testing, Blackbox testing, System testing, End to End testing and exploratory testing to uncover potential areas of improvement or user experience issues.
- · Responsible for testing the APIs using tool like Postman. Worked on HTTP, XML, REST, JSON requests.
- · Worked on WebEngage, CleverTap tool for tracking events & user statistics of the application.
- · Worked on Apollo 247 mobile application testing i.e native app testing with different OS like Android, iOS and mobile browser (mweb), on physical device and using Browser Stack tool.
- Performed exploratory testing to uncover potential issues not covered by predefined test cases.
- Conducted usability testing to evaluate the user experience of software applications.
- Expertise in testing multiple platforms and browsers at the Enterprise level on Windows and iOS platforms.
- Responsible for defining and preparing test data for test & production environments.
- Performed UI/UX testing and Ad-hoc testing weekly along with Backward compatibility testing (Mobile app) before a new release.
- Possess ability to collaborate with cross functional teams like designers, Product managers, developers and other team members to understand project requirement, test objectives, analyze test results, locate problems, identify root causes, for smooth SIT/UAT and to ensure quality throughout the software development life cycle.
- · Possess strong ability to focus on deadlines and deliverables & ensure the aptitude to discover defects and bugs quickly.

MG-Holidays

Cybage Software Pvt Ltd

- Responsible for Blackbox testing of B2B application as a Manual Tester.
- · Performed manual testing, Sanity testing and UAT for the application post production release.
- Possess experience in authoring and executing the test scenarios/testcases manually.
- · Effectively communicated on the testing, including the planning, preparation, execution, and results.
- \cdot Well versed with different test case designing and execution techniques.
- Troubleshooted errors/problems encountered during testing, did the defect triage and root cause analysis and provided feedback to the Development team.
- Actively contributed to the improvement of testing processes and methodologies. Provided feedback on areas for process enhancement and efficiency gains.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Created QA sign off document/ Release notes for every package release.
- · Conducted post release / post implementation testing.
- · Familiar with different development methodologies such as Waterfall, Agile, Scrum, V-Model.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

Savitribai Phule Pune University · Nashik · 2018

SKILLS

Web technologies :- HTML, CSS.

Documentation tools :- MS Office .

Database: - SQL, Mysql.

Testing skills: - SDLC, STLC, Agile concepts, Testing concepts & techniques, Quality Assurance concepts & QA methodology, HTTP, JSON, REST, XML, Ability to create quality test plans, test cases, Regression & negative testing, UI & compatibility testing, Defect or bug tracking, Test strategies, Requirement Traceability Matrix.

CI/CD, Project management tools: - JIRA, TFS, Git, Jenkins, Confluence, Trello, TestRail, Zephyr.

Testing Tools: - Postman Tool, Burp Suite, Browser Stack, Kibana, WebEngage, Appsflyer, Clevertap, Soap UI, Selenium automation(Beginner).

Soft skills: - Strong organizational skill, Strong analysis & problem solving skills, Excellent communication & Collaboration skills, Experience working in fast paced environment, Strong attention to detail, Effective planning and ability to work independently.